

Profile

My approach focuses on branding, modern UI/UX patters and a holistic user-centric design. My coding background enables me to integrate responsive design from wireframes to prototype. My experience gives me insight into creating modern and accessible design that cater to user needs.

Contact

+ 1 917-675-3074

New York, NY

Rafaella np@hotmail.com

Employment History

UX/UI Designer at FoxGroove.

May 2022 — January 2023

- Translated the entire desktop platform into responsive screens, maintaining flow and design patterns. Use of animation on mobile screens to enhance user interaction.
- Collaborated in the design system development, assets and components/variants.
- Implemented modern and accessible design for mobile screens and was part of VQA process.
- Designed prototypes for enterprise-level SaaS systems in the healthcare industry.

UX/UI Designer at Freedom Mortgage.

December 2021 — May 2022

- Created wireframes, high fidelity mockups using inVision and Sketch.
- Usability tests to validate designs with usertesting.com.
- Worked in Agile environment and designed with ADA and WCAG guidelines.
- Collaborated with Marketing team to ensure consistent brand use across digital channels, developed and maintained digital standards and functional specs and participated in cross-functional digital initiatives.

UX/UI Designer at HomeOnCall.

February 2021 — April 2021

- Created an entire CRM dashboard (500 clients) from scratch with data visualization.
- Designed user flows to improve data organization.
- High fidelity prototype for desktop screen through iterative design process.

UX/UI Designer at F&E Media.

October 2019 — February 2021

- Up 10% conversion rate, customer engagement 15%, 100% retention for 2 years.
- Developed a static website with HTML, CSS & JS and designed UI elements.

Education

BS Bachelor of Science in Business, Colorado State University - Global Campus Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp, Columbia University, New York

Courses

UI/UX Design Specialization, CALARTS - Coursera

Marketing Summer Courses, Fashion Institute of Technology, New York

Links

https://rafaellanicoletti.com

Skills

HTML5

CSS

Design Systems

InVision

Figma

Sketch

User Testing

Adobe Creative Suite

ADA / WCAG

Adobe XD